General Motors  
U.S. Consumer Privacy Statement
================================================

Last updated: June 17, 2026

[View and print](https://www.gm.com/content/dam/company/docs/us/en/gmcom/privacy-statement/US_Consumer_Privacy_Statement_June_2026.pdf) our entire U.S. Consumer Privacy Statement (PDF)

We envision a world with zero crashes, zero emissions and zero congestion. To achieve this bold vision, we collect information about you and the world around you. This data helps power the products and services we offer, improve your experience and safety in your vehicle, and advance future technologies like electric vehicles and autonomous driving.

We are committed to providing you with a trusted experience and respecting your privacy when it comes to personal information. When we say Personal Information, we mean information that describes, relates to, or could reasonably be linked to you.

This Privacy Statement includes details about:

*   Personal Information we collect from and about you
*   How we use this Personal Information
*   How and when we disclose Personal Information, and
*   Your privacy rights and choices  

Table of Contents

What this Privacy Statement covers
----------------------------------

**GM affiliates:** Our Privacy Statement covers Personal Information that GM collects online and offline across all GM brands of products, services, websites and apps. When we say GM, we mean General Motors Holdings LLC and its affiliates based in the United States. These include brands like Cadillac, Buick, GMC, Chevrolet, OnStar, Fleet, GM Energy, ACDelco, Car Bravo, and Future Roads.

**Additional Information for California Consumers:** Our California supplement to this Privacy Statement is available [here](https://www.gm.com/california-privacy-statement).

**Washington Health Policy:** Our Washington Health Policy supplement to this Privacy Statement is available [here](https://www.gm.com/washington-health-policy).  

#### What This Privacy Statement Doesn’t Cover

**Certain GM affiliates:** This Privacy Statement does not apply to products or services offered by GM Financial or General Motors Insurance. Please review their privacy statements available on their websites.

**GM dealers:** Dealers that sell or lease GM vehicles are separate legal entities from GM with their own privacy practices. This Privacy Statement applies to Personal Information the dealer discloses to us, but it does not apply to any other collection, use, or disclosure of Personal Information by dealers. We encourage you to contact your GM dealer if you have questions about its privacy practices.

**Third-party services:** When you use GM products and services, you may access third-party services, applications, and websites not offered or controlled by GM. These may be available on your vehicle, such as Google Maps or SiriusXM, or by downloading an application to your connected vehicle through Google Play. We recommend that you review the privacy disclosures and permissions of these third-party services before using them. Unless we expressly say otherwise, this GM Privacy Statement does not apply to your use of these third-party services or any Personal Information third-party services may collect, use, or disclose.

**GM employees and candidates for employment:** Candidates for employment at GM have a separate privacy statement and should visit [https://search-careers.gm.com/en/privacy/](https://search-careers.gm.com/en/privacy/) to learn more. Current and former GM employees can find the privacy statement applicable to their relationship with GM on the company intranet site or via their human resources representative.

**De-identified data:** We may use technical measures to remove information that could reasonably identify you or your vehicle. We take reasonable steps to prevent this de-identified data from being re associated with you and require the same safeguards from any third parties we share it with. De-identified data is not Personal Information and may be used and disclosed for purposes not described in this Privacy Statement.

Personal information we collect
-------------------------------

GM offers a variety of products, apps and services. GM may collect Personal Information directly from you or through your interaction with our products or services, or we may receive Personal Information about you from: dealers, licensors, service providers, business partners, advertising platforms or third-party sources. For example, GM collects Personal Information about you when you:

*   Interact with us online, including while researching and shopping for products and services, engaging with our call centers, interacting with your GM account, interacting with email or other marketing and promotional activities, and participating in the My GM Rewards loyalty program
*   Buy or lease a GM vehicle from GM dealers or interact with them online about our or their products and services
*   Have your vehicle serviced by a GM dealer or other business that you may use to maintain or service your GM vehicle
*   Enroll in OnStar and use OnStar services
*   Use other products and services GM develops, including our myChevrolet, myBuick, myGMC or myCadillac vehicle mobile apps (Vehicle Mobile Apps) or our Home Energy Products, such as vehicle-to-home solutions or stationary home energy storage (Home Energy Products), or connect non-GM products such as your solar panels to our Home Energy Products

We may combine information that we receive from various sources, including third-party sources, with information you provide and use or disclose it for the purposes identified in this Privacy Statement.

The types of Personal Information that GM collects about you when you interact with us include:  

#### Identifiers

Such as your name, postal address, email address, screen name, photo, account ID, customer number, or telephone number. In limited circumstances, GM may collect a Social Security Number, for example if you win a sweepstakes or receive compensation that must be reported for government tax purposes.

#### Digital Activity Information

Such as your IP address, browser type and settings, device type and settings, operating system and settings, unique device identifier, cookie data, associated identifying and usage information of computers and mobile devices that interact with our products, and information about your use of our products and services, such as wireless network usage, infotainment system usage, Wi-Fi data usage, and Vehicle Mobile Apps.

#### Vehicle Information

Such as information about your vehicle or information that is obtained from your vehicle and linked to you or reasonably can be linked to you. For example, we may be able to link information to you from your vehicle, including license plate number and vehicle identification number (VIN), or vehicle status, including mileage, oil/battery status, ignition, window, door/trunk lock status, vehicle diagnostic information, EV charging and discharging and stationary energy storage details.

#### Geolocation Information

Including the location of a vehicle, mobile device, or other device that is linked to you or can reasonably be linked to you, such as when you use our Vehicle Mobile Apps. For geolocation information for OnStar, see below.

#### Demographic or Protected Classification Information

Such as gender, date of birth, marital status, household composition, or veteran or military status. We may collect demographic or protected classification information when you respond to surveys or market research, interact with our websites and shopping tools, sign up for a GM account, participate in My GM Rewards, or enroll in OnStar.

#### Commercial Information

Such as (a) information about your vehicle purchases or leases, including financing information, and information disclosed to us about your vehicle when it is serviced by a GM dealer or other third party such as service history, mileage, and diagnostic information, (b) information about your relationships with third parties in connection with your use of GM products and services, such as GM dealers, energy utilities, and companies offering or operating in-vehicle applications, (c) information about your accounts with us, (d) relationships you have with GM in addition to the purchase and servicing of your vehicle, such as My GM Rewards, a My GM Rewards Card, or OnStar or (e) information about how you use our products and services, such as home energy usage, home charging preferences, and records of your use of public charging.

#### Payment Information

We may collect payment information, including credit card information, when you interact with our websites and shopping tools, get a GM account, participate in My GM Rewards or enroll in OnStar.

#### Audio or Video Information

Such as recordings of your voice when you use voice commands, call GM customer support for help with GM products and services, or interact with OnStar advisors in the event of, for example, a vehicle crash or health or safety emergency; or photographs and videos that you may submit for contests, sweepstakes, social sharing, or other purposes in connection with your use of our products and services.

When a vehicle is enrolled in OnStar services, GM may collect additional types of Personal Information about you, including:

#### Geolocation Information

We may collect the location of the vehicle, including Precise Geolocation, while the vehicle is in use, upon the occurrence of certain events, and to deliver OnStar services as set forth in the OnStar Services Consent available [here](https://www.onstar.com/legal/user-terms/onstar-services-consent). Precise Geolocation is location information that identifies a location within a radius of 1850 feet. In limited circumstances GM may still collect Geolocation Information from a disconnected vehicle. Please see “Disconnecting your connected vehicle” below for more information.

#### Driver Behavior Information

Information about how you drive a vehicle that is linked or reasonably linkable to you, such as vehicle speed, seatbelt use information, information about braking and acceleration habits, and related trip time and duration. We may also collect Seatbelt Information (whether the driver or passenger seatbelts are latched or unlatched) while the vehicle is in use to deliver OnStar services as set forth in the OnStar Services Consent available. We do not collect camera images or video from any sensors on the interior of your vehicle, such as the sensors integrated into the Super Cruise Drive Monitoring System, but we may collect data other than images or video that is derived from these sensors, such as when your vehicle detects a distracted or drowsy driver. We do not collect camera images or video from any sensors on the interior of your vehicle, such as the sensors integrated into the Super Cruise Drive Monitoring System, but we may collect data other than images or video that is derived from these sensors, such as when your vehicle detects a distracted or drowsy driver.

#### AI Assistant Interaction Information

If you use artificial intelligence (AI) assistants in your vehicle or our Vehicle Mobile Apps, we may collect information about those interactions. This includes information you choose to share with the assistant and information about what you are trying to do when you use it. Depending on how you use the assistants, this may include, for example, the transcript of your interactions, places you ask it to navigate to, your contacts, call history, and details or comments related to the topics you discuss with it.

#### External Vehicle Camera and Sensor Information

We may collect images and video from your vehicle’s external cameras and sensors (such as radar) only with your consent or when your vehicle detects a safety event (such as a collision or automatic emergency braking system engagement). You can change your consent anytime online in the Data and Privacy section of your GM account by logging in at OnStar.com or your vehicle’s brand website. Exterior camera images and video may capture your surrounding environment and individuals incidentally nearby. We may collect road information from your vehicle’s exterior cameras, such as signs and lane markings, even when images and video are not collected.

**Cookies & Tracking Technologies** GM may use software tools like cookies and pixel tags to better understand how you use our websites, applications, emails, and advertisements.

*   Cookies are small files saved on your device
*   Pixel tags are tiny images embedded in content

These tools may work across your devices and collect information such as your activity in our Vehicle Mobile Apps, browser type, IP address, pages visited, activities conducted on the page, and the day and time of your visit.

These tools show us how people interact with us—for example, by clicking an ad, navigating a webpage, or opening, clicking, or forwarding an email—and when and where those interactions occur. They also collect information about the device and browser you use, such as its name, version, operating system, and settings. In addition, they may collect network information and URL that referred you to our websites or applications.

We use and disclose information collected through these tracking technologies, sometimes combined with other information we collect, for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement, including to ensure our websites and apps function properly, to coordinate your profile across different websites, to understand who interacts with our websites, applications, emails, and advertisements, and to reach you through third-party advertising networks. Some third-party advertising networks and other businesses who operate these tracking technologies may also use this information to personalize ads you see on third-party websites.

**Event Data Recorder (EDR) information**  
Vehicles are required to include Event Data Recorders (EDR) that capture details in the event of an accident. GM does not access your vehicle’s EDR system without your consent. For additional information about EDR data, please see your owner’s manual.

How we use this Personal Information
------------------------------------

The Personal Information GM collects may be used for the following purposes:  

#### Products and services

*   Provide our products, programs, and services, such as to access your GM Account, save a vehicle configuration, use vehicle diagnostic tools, or, if you have an electric vehicle, to deliver charging programs
*   Provide connected vehicle products and services, such as access OnStar advisors, enable in-vehicle connectivity, enable entertainment or navigation and stolen vehicle assistance
*   Develop new products and services, including connected, autonomous, and car-sharing products and services
*   Provide customer and vehicle support and services (such as recall information)
*   Administer and validate warranties
*   Conduct internal research and evaluate performance to develop, improve, repair, and enhance the quality, safety, and security of our vehicles, products, services, and technology.
*   Administer your account(s) and process your payments for products and services
*   Operate our websites and applications, including online registration processes
*   Improve your online experiences, such as autofill data fields on our websites
*   Maintain your account log-in information or contact information on Request a Quote forms between visits or locating a nearby dealer
*   For operations and compliance purposes

#### Communication, marketing and advertising

*   Maintain customer relationships and communicate with you
*   Customize and improve communication content and your experience with GM
*   Marketing and analytics purposes, such as providing more useful and relevant advertising to you on GM and non-GM websites about the products and services that may interest you
*   Measure site activity, identify visitors to our websites, provide a better user experience, and tailor our marketing communications
*   Evaluate our online advertising campaigns or tailor promotions and other marketing messages to you across your devices
*   Administer your participation in contests, quizzes, surveys, promotions, and offers

#### Purchasing, rewards and incentive programs

*   Verify eligibility for vehicle purchase or incentive programs
*   Verify eligibility for a My GM Rewards Card and to provide My GM Rewards Card account management services
*   To support the electronic signature and delivery process between you and your dealer
*   Facilitate and support GM dealer, supplier, and community development programs.
*   Enroll you in programs, services, or memberships with businesses that can assist with how you use your electric vehicle (such as energy utility companies and charge station operators)

#### Safety, compliance and legal

*   Protect the safety of you or others
*   Evaluate or conduct a merger, divestiture, acquisition, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of our assets
*   Comply with legal, regulatory, or contractual requirements
*   Protect our rights, such as investigating, establishing, exercising, preparing for, or defending legal claims
*   Prevent, detect, protect against, or respond to security incidents, identity theft, harassment, malicious or deceptive activities, or any illegal activity or preserve the integrity or security of systems; or investigate, report, or prosecute those responsible for any such action

#### Connected vehicle Personal Information uses

When you enroll in OnStar, GM and GM affiliates may use Driver Behavior Information, Precise Geolocation Information, External Vehicle Camera Images and Video, and AI Assistant Interaction Information for the limited purposes outlined below.

*   To deliver our products and services where the information is reasonably necessary or otherwise compatible with your reasonable expectations, such as:
    *   seatbelt information in the event of a crash
    *   Precise Geolocation Information to provide vehicle locate features in our Vehicle Mobile Apps, to provide turn-by-turn routing information to you via OnStar, or to assist in the location or recovery of a vehicle reasonably identified as stolen
    *   AI Assistant Interaction Information to enable our AI Assistants to respond to your request
*   As reasonably necessary to protect the safety, property, or rights of us, our customers, or members of the public
*   For operations, compliance, or warranty purposes
*   For internal research or product development
*   To prevent, detect, protect against, or respond to security incidents, identity theft, harassment, malicious or deceptive activities, or any illegal activity; and preserve the integrity or security of systems; or investigate, report, or prosecute those responsible for any such action
*   Comply with legal, regulatory, or contractual requirements
*   Protect our rights, such as investigating, establishing, exercising, preparing for, or defending legal claims

Disclosing and selling of Personal Information
----------------------------------------------

We may disclose Personal Information within GM, including to GM affiliates. We may also disclose Personal Information to the following categories of third parties. Some of these disclosures may qualify as “sales” under some state laws.  

#### Disclosures

*   GM dealers and their service providers to deliver their products and services to you and to GM licensees;
*   Service providers who help us provide our products and services to you, such as companies that administer our contests and promotions, host or operate our websites, send communications, perform data analytics, or process, store, or manage credit card information
*   Fleet owners, dealers or rental car companies, for service or maintenance of their vehicles that you may use
*   Emergency service and roadside assistance providers to deliver related services and to protect your safety or the safety of others (for example, to help you in an emergency)
*   Wireless service providers, to deliver cellular or Wi-Fi connectivity to your vehicle
*   Third parties where you have chosen to receive a service from them or authorized them to request data from GM (for example, financial organizations who offer financing for the purchase or lease of GM vehicles or the My GM Rewards GM Card program)
*   Third parties for research and development purposes (such as university research institutes for improving highway safety)
*   In connection with the sale, transfer or financing of a GM business or its assets, including any such activities associated with a bankruptcy proceeding
*   As required or permitted by law, such as to comply with a civil, criminal, or regulatory inquiry, investigation, subpoena, or summons by federal, state, local, or other governmental authorities
*   As permitted by law, such as (a) when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, your safety, or the safety of others, (b) to prevent, detect, protect against, or respond to security incidents, identity theft, fraud, harassment, malicious or deceptive activities, or other illegal activity, or preserve the integrity or security of systems, (c) to investigate, establish, exercise, prepare for, or defend legal claims, or (d) to conduct screening to ensure you are not on any government list of restricted parties

#### Disclosures that may qualify as “sales”

Some of the disclosures of the Personal Information listed above may qualify as “sales” under some state laws. Those categories may include:  

*   Identifiers, Digital Activity Information, and VIN may be disclosed to companies with which GM enters into business or marketing arrangements, such as third-party advertising networks, GM dealers, and financial institutions that GM works with to offer co-branded credit cards.
*   Commercial information may be disclosed to GM dealers, and to financial institutions to which GM licenses personal information to offer co-branded credit cards.

#### Connected vehicle Personal Information disclosures

When you enroll in OnStar, GM may disclose Driver Behavior Information, Precise Geolocation Information, Exterior Vehicle Camera Images and Video, and AI Assistant Interaction Information to our affiliates and the categories of third parties mentioned below for the following limited purposes:

#### Driver Behavior Information and Precise Geolocation Information

*   Affiliates (such as GM Financial) or third-party services providers (such as wireless connectivity providers) where you have chosen to receive a product or service from them or have authorized them to request data from GM
*   Emergency service and roadside assistance providers to deliver services and to protect life or physical safety (for example, to help you in an emergency)
*   General Motors Insurance when you have given your affirmative consent to disclose Driver Behavior Information or Precise Geolocation Information for usage-based insurance offers or to help determine your rate for an insurance quote or policy
*   Service providers who work on our behalf and who do not have an independent right to use the Driver Behavior Information or Precise Geolocation Information, such as companies that help us develop our products and services or perform data analytics
*   Fleet owners, dealers, or rental car companies, for service or maintenance of their vehicles that you may use
*   As permitted by law, such as (a) when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, your safety, or the safety of others, (b) to prevent, detect, protect against, or respond to security incidents, identity theft, fraud, harassment, malicious or deceptive activities, or other illegal activity, or preserve the integrity or security of systems, or (c) to investigate, establish, exercise, prepare for, or defend legal claims
*   As reasonably necessary to comply with a lawful government request, regulatory requirement, legal order, or similar obligation, which must be in the form of a warrant or court order, absent exigent circumstances or applicable statutory authority

#### Exterior Vehicle Camera Images and Video

*   Service providers who work on our behalf and who do not have an independent right to use the exterior vehicle camera images and video, such as companies that help us develop our products and services
*   As permitted by law, such as (a) when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, your safety, or the safety of others, (b) to prevent, detect, protect against, or respond to security incidents, identity theft, fraud, harassment, malicious or deceptive activities, or other illegal activity, or preserve the integrity or security of systems, or (c) to investigate, establish, exercise, prepare for, or defend legal claims
*   As reasonably necessary to comply with a lawful government request, regulatory requirement, legal order, or similar obligation, which must be in the form of a warrant or court order, absent exigent circumstances or applicable statutory authority

#### AI Assistant Interaction Information

*   Service providers who work on our behalf and who do not have an independent right to use the AI Assistant Interaction Information, such as companies that help us develop our products and services
*   As permitted by law, such as (a) to prevent, detect, protect against, or respond to security incidents, or preserve the integrity or security of systems, or (b) to investigate, establish, exercise, prepare for, or defend legal claims
*   As reasonably necessary to comply with a lawful government request, regulatory requirement, legal order, or similar obligation, which must be in the form of a warrant or court order, absent exigent circumstances or applicable statutory authority

Connected Vehicle Features and Controls
---------------------------------------

#### Sharing your connected vehicle

The nature of our connected vehicles means that there may be circumstances where you might let someone else use a product or service that we provide to you (for example, you enrolled your vehicle in OnStar and then let someone else drive the vehicle). It is important that if you do let someone else use one of our products or services, you inform them of this Privacy Statement and of the privacy choices that you have made.

#### Selling or transferring your connected vehicle

If you sell or otherwise transfer your vehicle, we strongly encourage you to delete all Personal Information (such as contacts, address searches, saved map addresses, or preferences) from the vehicle and contact us to transfer or cancel your account. If you do not delete this Personal Information, it may remain in the vehicle and may be accessible to future users of the vehicle. For instructions on how to delete Personal Information from your vehicle or restore factory settings, please refer to your owner’s manual.

#### Location Services

Some model year 2019 and later vehicles may have an option to disable location services for OnStar that you can access through the Privacy Settings in your vehicle’s infotainment system. If you disable location services, we may still collect Geolocation Information from the vehicle in the event of an emergency (such as in the event of a crash, when the emergency call button is pressed, or where there is overheating of a high voltage battery).

#### Exterior Camera and Sensor Data

For Model Year 2025 and newer vehicles, we may ask for your consent to collect video and measurements (not audio) from your vehicle’s built-in external cameras and sensors of the road and your surroundings during operation. For more information about this Exterior Camera and Sensor Data collection and to update your vehicle’s settings, visit the Data and Privacy section of your GM account, at [https://experience.gm.com/myaccount/privacy](https://experience.gm.com/myaccount/privacy). You can also visit Privacy Settings in your vehicle’s infotainment system for additional choices, including the ability to pause this data collection.

#### Disconnecting your connected vehicle

You can disconnect your vehicle and unenroll from OnStar at any time by contacting an Advisor by phone at 1-888-4ONSTAR (1-888-466-7827) or by pushing the OnStar blue button in your vehicle. We may still collect Geolocation Information and Vehicle Information from your vehicle when the OnStar blue button is pressed to restore cellular connectivity with GM. For battery electric vehicles, if you unenroll your vehicle from OnStar, the overheating of a high voltage battery may trigger GM’s collection of Geolocation Information and Vehicle Information from the vehicle.

Marketing and communications
----------------------------

GM uses Personal Information to market and communicate with you. You can adjust these preferences or access and update your details as described below.  

#### Marketing and communications preferences

We may communicate with you by mail, telephone, e-mail, text or other electronic messages, through the in-vehicle infotainment unit or OnStar system or via our websites and applications. Texting with GM is subject to the GM Consolidated Texting Policy (Texting Policy), available at [https://www.gm.com/texting-policy](https://www.gm.com/texting-policy). Reply STOP to opt-out of any text message program or HELP for support information. Text message program frequency may vary and standard text message and data rates may apply. We do not purchase, sell, or rent GM text message program opt-ins or share these opt-ins with third parties for their own use.

If you do not want to receive marketing communications from GM, please visit our Consumer Preference System website at [https://www.gmcontactpreferences.com](https://www.gmcontactpreferences.com/). This will allow you to opt-out of communications or to change previously submitted opt-out preferences. You can also call 1-866-MYPRIVACY (1-866-697-7482) to opt-out of direct mail communications, as well as telephone and email communications, or to change previously submitted opt-out preferences. When you opt-out of receiving marketing communications from GM, Personal Information about you may still be used for the other transactional and service-related purposes described in this Privacy Statement (such as vehicle support and service).

To unsubscribe from a particular email newsletter or other communication (such as My GMLINK Service Reminders), you should follow the instructions in the email or on a related website.

#### Targeted advertising

Our ad networks may offer ways to adjust your ad preferences, including the Digital Advertising Alliance's Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising ([https://AboutAds.info](https://aboutads.info/)). If you do not wish to receive personalized advertising or content from us while visiting non-GM websites, you may click on the AdChoices icon or link located at the bottom of our websites, where available, to learn more about the companies GM uses for personalized advertising or by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance’s Opt-Out page for instructions on how to opt-out. Opting out of personalized advertising will not opt you out of all GM advertising, but rather only those GM advertisements that are personalized to your interests by the companies GM uses to display advertising on non-GM sites. After opting out of personalized advertising, you may still continue to see GM advertisements on non-GM websites based upon your interactions with the non-GM websites on which our advertisements appear.

#### Access and update your account and contact information

You can access your GM online account to view or update Personal Information about you in that account, or contact us at the numbers provided below.

Please call the Customer Assistance Center that is specific to your vehicle:

Buick 1-800-521-7300  
Cadillac 1-800-458-8006  
Chevrolet 1-800-222-1020  
GMC 1-800-462-8782  
OnStar 1-888-466-7827  
Saturn 1-800-553-6000  
HUMMER (2010 and prior model years) 1-866-486-6376  
Pontiac 1-800-762-2737

For inquiries about how the Personal Information you submit to the Investors portion of GM’s website or to GM Stockholder Services is handled, please call 1-313-667-1432.

You may update My GM Rewards Cards contact information, such as name, address, phone number and email address, by logging into the Account portion of the website listed on the back of your card. You may withdraw from participation in the My GM Rewards program at any time by contacting a My GM Rewards Member Support Specialist at 1-844-764-2665. If you have a question or concern about the privacy practices of the My GM Rewards Cards or the My GM Rewards Card websites, please contact us by sending an email from the Contact Us section. For a complete description of the most current eligible transactions, benefits and participating companies, as well as details on earning and redeeming points, go to  [https://experience.gm.com/rewards](https://experience.gm.com/rewards).

Your privacy rights
-------------------

#### How to submit a request

Depending on where you live, you may have certain rights related to Personal Information about you. To exercise the rights described below, or to see what rights may be available in your state, please submit a verifiable consumer request to us by either:

*   Completing GM’s [U.S. Consumer Privacy Request Form](https://www.gm.com/consumer-privacy)
*   Calling us at 1-866-MYPRIVACY (1-866-697-7482) 

We do not accept consumer privacy requests made by email.  

#### Rights available to you

GM offers the following privacy rights to all consumers covered by this Privacy Statement:   

*   Access and obtain a portable copy of my Personal Information
*   Correct my Personal Information
*   Delete my Personal Information

Depending on where you reside, you may also be able to request additional privacy rights that may include:  

*   Opt-out of processing my Personal Information for targeted advertising (in California, this is called “Do Not Share My Personal Information”)
*   Opt-out of selling my Personal Information
*   Opt-out of certain types of automated processing of Personal Information
*   Obtain a list of categories of Third Parties Receiving Personal Information
*   Obtain a list of Third Parties Receiving Personal Information

#### Processing expectations

We do not discriminate against consumers who exercise these rights. We take reasonable steps to respond to all requests and will work to process your request in accordance with the laws that apply where you reside. Our processing time may vary, and in some cases, we may require up to 45 days to process your request. We may retain the Personal Information you submit with your request for as long as required or permitted by applicable law.

For consumers who submit a request to “Access my Personal Information,” we will also notify you of vehicles that we associate with you as the vehicle owner or the account holder for vehicle services, and the categories of data that we collected about these vehicles. These categories of vehicle data may include Driving Behavior Information, Geolocation Information, and Vehicle Information. If we notify you that GM has collected categories of vehicle data for a vehicle that you own and operate, you may submit a request for additional access to the vehicle data that relates to your vehicle use by following the instructions provided with that notice.

#### Authorizing an agent

You may be permitted by law to authorize someone else to act as your agent to exercise privacy rights on your behalf. In such cases, your authorized agent must provide documentation supporting his or her authority to make this request on your behalf. In some cases, we may also require you to verify your identity directly with us and confirm the request before we will process it.

Further information about how to submit this request and the documentation we require to support it is available within our U.S. Consumer Privacy Request Form at [https://consumerprivacy.gm.com](https://consumerprivacy.gm.com/). Your authorized agent can also contact us at [gm.datacompliance@gm.com](mailto:gm.datacompliance@gm.com) to request a copy of our Authorized Agent Form and to submit this request on your behalf. Documentation supporting your authorized agent’s right to submit this request on your behalf, such as a copy of our Authorized Agent Form signed by you or a Power of Attorney, must be submitted with this request. If this request is submitted over the phone, your authorized agent will be asked to email supporting documentation to [gm.datacompliance@gm.com](mailto:gm.datacompliance@gm.com).

#### Verifying your request

For your protection, we take reasonable steps to verify all requests before they are processed. This may include, for example, a request from us for you to confirm your identity, to validate documents you submit to us, to verify your authority to make the request, or for other purposes. In all cases, we reserve the right to deny your request if we cannot verify you or your authority to make the request.

If we decline to take action regarding your request, we will notify you. You may have the right to appeal. To submit an appeal request, please contact us at [gm.datacompliance@gm.com](mailto:gm.datacompliance@gm.com).

#### Global Privacy Control

Our websites respond to the Global Privacy Control (GPC) signal when we detect that it is enabled on the web browser used to access them. We respond to your web browser’s GPC setting each time you visit our websites. When we detect the GPC signal, we honor this as your request to opt out of “sales” and certain types of targeted advertising at the web browser-level by turning off data collection by some website cookies and tracking technologies. We will not honor a prior web browser setting if you disable GPC in the web browser used to access our websites between visits, or if you later visit our websites from different devices or browsers that do not send the GPC signal. More information on how to use the GPC signal, including supported browsers, is available at [https://globalprivacycontrol.org/](https://globalprivacycontrol.org/). At this time, we do not honor “Do Not Track” signals if enabled in a web browser.

How we safeguard Personal Information
-------------------------------------

We maintain reasonable technical, administrative, and physical security and confidentiality measures designed to help protect Personal Information from unauthorized access or use. We also require (other than in certain emergency situations) third-party service providers acting on our behalf or with whom we disclose Personal Information to provide similar security and confidentiality measures. Learn more about cybersecurity at GM by visiting [https://gm.com/cybersecurity](https://gm.com/cybersecurity).

How long we keep Personal Information
-------------------------------------

We may keep the Personal Information we collect for as long as necessary for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement. We will de-identify or dispose of the Personal Information we collect when we no longer need it for the uses described in this Privacy Statement. De-identified data is not Personal Information and not subject to the retention periods described below.

More detailed information about the retention of Precise Geolocation Information, Driver Behavior Information (including seatbelt information), and Radio Listening Information is provided below. We no longer collect Radio Listening Information, but continue to retain previously collected Radio Listening Information for the purposes listed below.

Data may be retained for longer than the stated retention periods below if required to comply with legal or regulatory obligations. Under these circumstances, data will be deleted once the legal or regulatory obligations expire.

**Retention Schedule for the Following Data Associated with the Operation of Your GM Vehicle:**

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Type of Data** | **Purpose for Collection and/or Retention** | **Retention Period** |
| **Precise Geolocation Information** | *   To deliver our and our affiliates’ products and services to consumers, including: safety and security services, connected navigation services, ability to control various vehicle functions remotely via a mobile app, to provide Super Cruise services, and to provide EV health support<br>*   To protect the safety, property, or rights of us, our customers, or members of the public<br>*   For operations, compliance, or warranty purposes<br>*   For internal research or product development<br>*   To prevent, detect, protect against, or respond to security incidents, identity theft, harassment, malicious or deceptive activities, or any illegal activity; and preserve the integrity or security of systems; or investigate, report, or prosecute those responsible for any such action<br>*   Comply with legal, regulatory, or contractual requirements (see above for more information)<br>*   Protect our rights, such as investigating, establishing, exercising, preparing for, or defending legal claims | *   Up to 3 years from date of collection |
| **Seatbelt  Information** | *   To deliver our and our affiliates’ safety products and services to consumers<br>*   To protect the safety, property, or rights of us, our customers, or members of the public<br>*   For operations, compliance, or warranty purposes<br>*   For internal research or product development<br>*   To prevent, detect, protect against, or respond to security incidents, identity theft, harassment, malicious or deceptive activities, or any illegal activity; and preserve the integrity or security of systems; or investigate, report, or prosecute those responsible for any such action<br>*   Comply with legal, regulatory, or contractual requirements (see above for more information)<br>*   Protect our rights, such as investigating, establishing, exercising, preparing for, or defending legal claims | *   Up to 6 years from date of collection |
| **Driver Behavior Information linked to any of the following events: hard braking, hard acceleration, hard cornering, crossing of a designated high-speed threshold, or late-night driving, and trip time and duration for such events** | *   To deliver our affiliates’ products and<br>*   services to consumers<br>*   To protect the safety, property, or rights of us, our customers, or members of the public<br>*   For operations, compliance, or warranty purposes<br>*   For internal research or product development<br>*   To prevent, detect, protect against, or respond to security incidents, identity theft, harassment, malicious or deceptive activities, or any illegal activity; and preserve the integrity or security of systems; or investigate, report, or prosecute those responsible for any such action<br>*   Comply with legal, regulatory, or contractual requirements (see above for more information)<br>*   Protect our rights, such as investigating, establishing, exercising, preparing for, or defending legal claims | *   Up to 6 months from date of collection |
| **Radio Listening Information (data regarding the channel or station set in the vehicle)** | *   Comply with legal and regulatory requirements (see above for more information)<br>*   Protect our rights, such as investigating, establishing, exercising, preparing for, or defending legal claims | *   As necessary to comply with legal and regulatory requirements |

To the extent you have given us your affirmative consent to disclose Precise Geolocation Information and Driver Behavior Information to General Motors Insurance for usage-based insurance offers or to help determine your rate for an insurance quote or policy, General Motors Insurance may retain that data as explained below:

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Type of Data** | **Purpose for Collection and/or Retention** | **Retention Period** |
| **Precise Geolocation Information and Driver Behavior Information** | *   To evaluate insurance offerings and rates that may apply to you and present you with offers and related marketing for programs, services, or discounts for which you may be eligible<br>*   To deliver General Motors Insurance products and services<br>*   To conduct research to develop and improve its insurance offerings | *   Up to 3 years |
| *   Comply with legal and regulatory requirements for retaining data related to policies issued | *   Up to 10 years from policy expiration |

Children’s privacy
------------------

GM websites and other online and connected services do not target or knowingly collect or process any Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If we have actual knowledge that we inadvertently collected or processed Personal Information from a child under 13 years of age, we will dispose of such information.

We do not knowingly sell or process for targeted advertising the Personal Information of children we know to be under 16 years of age without affirmative authorization as required by law. If we have actual knowledge that we are selling or sharing Personal Information from a child at least 13 years of age but not yet 16 years of age, we require affirmative authorization from the individual. GM may collect or process Personal Information from children at least 13 years of age but not yet 16 years of age to deliver products and services.

If you are a parent or guardian and believe we have collected or processed Personal Information from your child without proper authorization, please contact us using the information in the “How to contact us” section of this Privacy Statement. We will take steps to delete the information as required by applicable law.

We do not sell or process for profiling or targeted advertising the Personal Information of children we know or should have known to be under 18 years of age.

International transfers of Personal Information
-----------------------------------------------

When GM and its affiliates in the United States, including OnStar, (GM U.S.), receive Personal Information from GM and affiliates outside the United States, (Non-U.S. Companies), we comply with applicable legal requirements providing adequate protection for the transfer of Personal Information to third countries.

We may store Personal Information in the United States, the European Economic Area (EEA), and other locations where we or our service providers maintain servers. With respect to such transfers from the EEA to the United States and other non-EEA jurisdictions, we implement standard contractual clauses and other mechanisms to protect such data.

Individuals that use products or services offered by Non-U.S. Companies may wish to raise any privacy questions with such company directly, including filing any requests to access customer data or exercise other privacy rights. Each Non-U.S. Company has a separate privacy statement that you can find by visiting its website. Individuals may also raise questions with GM U.S. using the contact details below.

In addition, anonymized and aggregated data from Non-U.S. Companies are disclosed with GM U.S. to evaluate or research the safety, quality, usage, and functionality of vehicles and services; to provide Non-U.S. Company customers with vehicle support and services; and to ensure accurate customer records and maintain customer relationships. Personal Information is also disclosed with GM U.S. in order to contact Non-U.S. Company customers about their vehicle or the services, or for marketing purposes, but only if the individual has opted in to receive marketing communications.

How to contact us
-----------------

If you have concerns or questions about GM's consumer privacy practices or this Privacy Statement you may contact us at 1-866-MYPRIVACY (1-866-697-7482). You may also contact GM Privacy by mail at Attn: GM Privacy, P.O. Box 1027, Warren, Michigan USA 48090-1027 or by email at [privacy@gm.com](mailto:privacy@gm.com).

Changes to this Privacy Statement
---------------------------------

We may amend this Privacy Statement from time to time. In some cases, we will notify you of this change by posting a new effective date at the top of this Privacy Statement and your continued use of our products and services covered by this Privacy Statement will mean you accept the changes. When there is a material change to this Privacy Statement, then we will notify you as required by law, such as by email or through a notice on the applicable website.

##### [Privacy Statement for OnStar Guardian](https://www.onstar.com/content/dam/onstar/na/us/en/index/legal/privacy-statement/02-pdfs/Privacy-Statement-for-OnStar-Guardian_2024.pdf)

##### [Previous Privacy Statements](https://www.gm.com/previous-statements)
